chordify.net 2019-06-09

# Privacy statement Chordify | Blog | Chordify | Tune Into Chords

_This privacy statement is based on the European GDPR and Dutch law. If you think your rights under your country’s legislation are not covered by this statement, please email us at_[ _privacy@chordify.net_](mailto:privacy@chordify.net) _before you use Chordify._

We have stored data and personal information since the very beginning of Chordify, and we have also always deemed privacy and data security of paramount importance. To comply with the European Regulation, called the AVG (Algemene verordening gegevensbescherming), (a.k.a. GDPR; effective date 25 May 2018), we have implemented extra measures.

To assist every Chordify user as best we can, and to achieve our goals, we will continue to store personal data, but thanks to the GDPR, our users are given even more rights, and we welcome that! We apply the amended privacy policy world-wide, so everyone will acquire the same rights. In this privacy statement, we explain as clearly as possible why and how we process your personal data.

We don’t have a Data Protection Officer (DPO), but we will assist you personally if you have any questions. For assistance, please contact us on [privacy@chordify.net.](mailto:privacy@chordify.net)

We are Chordify: a cross-platform e-learning tool that allows you to convert your music into chords. We started Chordify in 2013 to assist – and motivate –  both experienced and inexperienced musicians in learning and playing music. Chordify BV, Boterdiep 63, (9712 LK) Groningen is the Responsible Processor, as it is called in the GDPR, of your personal data.

Our growing team, who is committed to making the learning of music easier and more fun, consists of a varied range of music lovers. They have diverse skills in areas such as music and software technology, graphic and interactive design, content creation, and sales and business development.

This privacy statement applies to all our processing operations.

We process the following personal data:

First and last name, email address, profile information (shared by yourself in the community) (bio, favourite songs, play-along history) and profile picture, gender, participation details (of events, memberships and/or (winning) promotions), areas of interest (for example, ‘guitar’ or ‘newbie’), contact history, IP address, social ID, cookie ID (you can read more about cookies in our cookie statement) and user behaviour.

We process personal data for the following purposes:

  * Legal obligations

A part of our processing is required by law. This mainly concerns information necessary for our (financial) administration, and to comply with our tax and accounting obligations.

  * Membership administration and services

We keep track in our membership records of people who are Chordify members. We keep various personal details of contacts to run our services as best we can. For instance, we keep contact information in order to reach you, areas of interest so we can provide you with the best possible information and appealing content, and we process personal data for our market research and promotions. You can reach us through many different channels, like mail, email, Twitter, LinkedIn, Instagram and Facebook. To make this possible, we also process personal data.

Payment details

_The Chordify services payment process is entirely outsourced to Adyen, Paypal, Apple and Google_ _. We_ _therefore only store your payment details that we receive back from your chosen payment_   _provider. This doesn’t include your bank account number._

  * Newsletters and mailings

You can sign up for different types of newsletters from us. Sometimes personalised, and sometimes not. If you no longer wish to receive newsletters, you can unsubscribe in every email, and in your account settings, and you can indicate your preferences of the type of newsletters that you wish to receive in your account settings.

  * Recruitment (marketing)

Chordify is a growing company, and anticipates market developments. We therefore constantly recruit new members, (industrial) partners, musicians, music teachers and sometimes new colleagues too. To maintain contact with everyone, we also process their contact details and areas of interest.

We also process personal data for Chordify campaigns (and Chordify related campaigns). For example, IP address, cookie ID, social ID and/or surfing habits. We do this to show the most relevant ad in the right places.

We also use ‘custom target groups’ on social media platforms for Chordify (and related Chordify campaigns). We do this through Facebook, Twitter and through LinkedIn targeting. These platforms can show (personalized) ads. If you don’t want ads to be displayed through these platforms, you can unsubscribe yourself on the appropriate platforms. You can read how to do this on the following pages:

_Please note: the above opt-out doesn’t necessarily mean you’ll never get to see Chordify ads again, because we also focus ads on general target groups of which you might form part of._

  * Improved Chordify services

We also keep personal data for the improvement of our services. For example, we ‘log’ clicking behaviour on the website to analyse which numbers are most played along with, which articles are read the most, and open rates to see if our newsletters are relevant.

  * Gender and photos:

We also process your gender and your photos. Gender is processed to be able to address you in a more personal way. We process photos to add a nicer touch to our content (including your personal profile). These processing operations are (obviously) not used for any other purpose. Once again, if you have any questions, please let us know!

**You are under 16 years of age**

If you are under the age of 16, and you want to use Chordify, that’s only possible with your parents’ permission.

If you think we have collected personal data of a minor without parental consent, please contact us at [privacy@chordify.net](mailto:privacy@chordify.net).

Under the GDPR, everyone has a number of rights. We do our very best to comply with this as much as possible. If you have any tips or comments, please let us know! To enforce your rights, please contact us on [privacy@chordify.net](mailto:privacy@chordify.net). We ask you to specify as much as possible in your request what personal data it entails. We will respond to your request within four weeks. In case of a request for deletion, we will remove the relevant personal data as soon as possible, unless, and to the extent that the law requires us to keep the relevant personal data, and whether there are other urgent reasons that oppose removal. We will send you a confirmation message after a request for deletion has been carried out. If we haven’t removed the relevant personal data (or only did so partially), we will send you a message in which we explain why your request couldn’t (fully) be met. If we are not, or not completely able to determine to what personal data your request relates to, we may ask you to specify your request in more detail. We will then suspend the execution of the request until you have provided us with further details. You can also exercise your rights yourself, in your account environment:

  * Information and inspection: You can of course see which of your personal data we are processing. You can download the data stored about you in a ZIP file, in just a few clicks. [Settings] > [My Account] > [download user data].

_Please note: any files that you have uploaded to your Chordify Library are **not** automatically downloaded. You can download these one by one on the Song page of the relevant number. Just click on the menu button for the name of the artist and the song. [Music Profile] > [Uploads]._

  * Changes: If we have incorrect, or outdated data about you, you can adjust it yourself in [settings](https://chordify.net/user/account). You can also let us know what needs to be changed; We look forward to assist you.
  * Deletion: You can easily remove the personally identifiable information we have stored of you yourself by checking the box [delete all data stored about me] while deleting your Chordify Account. [Settings] > [My Account] > [delete account].
  * Processing this delete order takes up to 7 days to complete, for the following reasons: 
    * Administrative purposes (for example, handling payments or refunds, de-duplication).
    * We keep your account for 7 days after removal, because we can imagine the farewell may be heavier than thought. Deleted accounts are immediately invisible and idle, but this service allows users to reactivate their account if necessary.

_Take note! Contributions to the Chordify Community made by you (for example: chord edits, name changes, tags and set lists made by you, etc.) are **not** deleted automatically. Of course, we will ensure that your contributions are anonymised, and that they are in no way traceable to you any more._

_You can, of course, undo your contributions separately before you delete your account, but we assume that your love for Chordify and other music fans will never be quite over, and that other people will benefit from the preservation of your contributions. We love you too!_ _ _

_To continue to guarantee Chordify’s operation, we store log-data on our servers. Now matter how good our programmers are, it is difficult to ensure all personal data will disappear. We discard this log-data after 3 months at most, and therefore all bits of personal data are only then really wiped from Chordify._

_Take note! Something almost no one tells you is that it’s an illusion to think all your data have really been removed from the internet at just the touch of a button. There are many services on the internet that copy data, so perhaps you will still find your public Chordify profile somewhere on the internet until the end of time. So always be careful about what you share on-line._

  * Limitation: Are we processing your personal information unlawfully or incorrectly? You can also restrict its processing.
  * Objection (appeal): You can object against the processing of your personal data. If it involves marketing, we end the processing as soon as possible.
  * Transferability: It is a right under the GDPR to transfer your personal data, or to have it transferred. Although we don’t really think this is really relevant to our service, we will gladly assist you if necessary. You can read how you can download your own information under the above heading ‘Information and inspection’.

You can also:

  * Revoke permission: for example, to receive emails (you do that in settings, or via the link in a mailing sent by Chordify). If you want to withdraw your permission for any other processing, please contact us.
  * Submit a complaint with the Personal Data Authority (PDA): If you believe we do not act in accordance with privacy laws, we would like to hear it. You can also submit a complaint with the PDA in this regard, after 25 May 2018. At the moment, you can only send tips to the PDA, using [this form](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/nl/contact-met-de-autoriteit-persoonsgegevens/tip-ons). And finally, you always have the right to go to court to deal with your complaint.

We will not retain personal information for longer than necessary for the purposes for which we have collected it, unless the law requires us to keep it longer (for example, for our accounting).

As explained above, we process some data to perform a legal obligation, and some to perform a contract with you as a user (subscription, event). We also process personal data because, as stated in the GDPR, we have a legitimate interest in it. This means we may process your data because it is necessary for our business activities, as long as your privacy interests are not affected. We may also do so in the interest of our partners. If you want to know more about the trade-off’s we make as part of our legitimate interest, you know how to find us! Finally, we process some data with your permission: this specifically involves on-line tracking methods. You can always withdraw that consent.

We assign external service providers to carry out our own services. They are not ´third-party receivers’, but are called processors. For example, we work with Adyen, a payment service; we periodically carry out user surveys on our website using Typeform; and we use Google Analytics to gain a better understanding about how our service is used. These parties process personal data on Chordify’s behalf. We have concluded what is called processing agreements for this purpose.

Sometimes, we are required by law to provide personal data to third parties; for example, to the tax authorities.

The Chordify websites include many references to other websites. Chordify is not responsible for the way in which those parties process personal data.

You can read the privacy statement of the relevant organization, and please do let us know if you have found a particular link on chordify.net which is not OK!

Version

We can change or modify this Privacy statement. We therefore recommend that you regularly read this privacy statement for changes. This Privacy statement was last amended on May 22th 2018.

We use cookies on the Chordify website and apps. We do this to improve our services, to ensure the service functions optimally, to conduct campaigns efficiently and for the purposes as described in this privacy statement.

Cookies are small text files that are placed on a computer, tablet or mobile phone by a web page. You can choose what types of cookies we may keep of you. The following is a list of cookies placed by the Chordify services, and what we are using them for:

Chordify uses Analytics cookies to examine the use of Chordify products. We place a persistent cookie on your computer or your mobile device, so we can understand how and how often Chordify is used. Based on this information we can make adjustments if necessary, to ensure Chordify works optimally.

Name: NID  
Sender.google.com  
Duration: 7 months

Name: _ga  
Sender: .chordify.net  
Duration: 2 years

Name: _gat  
Sender: .chordify.net  
Duration: 1 hour

Name: _gid  
Sender: .chordify.net  
Duration: 1 day

Chordify processes anonymous statistics about visits to its website. This is done with a Web Analytics System. The following data is stored in the Web Analytics System using cookies:

  * The IP address.
  * Technical characteristics such as the browser you are using (e.g. Chrome, Safari, Internet Explorer, or Firefox) and your computer screen resolution.
  * The source from which you surfed to Chordify (e.g. Google, Facebook, or directly).
  * When and how long you visit and use the Chordify products.
  * Which features you are using in the Chordify products.
  * Which pages you visit on the Chordify products.

Name: dzr_uniq_id  
Sender: Deezer  
Duration: 6 months

Name: lang  
Sender: .chordify.net  
Duration: 1 day

Name: sid  
Sender: Deezer  
Duration: session

Name: PREF  
Sender: .youtube  
Durationr: 8 months

Name: user  
Sender: .chordify.net  
Duration: 1 years

Name: VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
Sender: .youtube  
Duration: 6 months

Name: YSC  
Sender: .youtube  
Duration: sessie

_Social Cookies make the use of Chordify more accessible, and the experience more fun and more personal. Cookies are necessary for the various integrations of social platforms; but you can also use Chordify without these links. We will now deal with the various social cookies._

Name: datr  
Sender: .facebook  
Duration: 2 years

Name: c_user  
Sender: .facebook  
Duration: 3 months

Name: xs  
Sender: .facebook  
Duration: 3 months

Name: fr  
Sender: .facebook  
Duration: 3 months

Name: sb  
Sender: .facebook  
Duration: 2 years

Name: pl  
Sender: .facebook  
Duration: 3 months

Name: cmp649170965  
Sender: .trackcmp.com  
Duration: 1 maand

Name: DSID  
Sender: .doubleclick.net  
Duration: 1 hour

Name: IDE  
Sender: .doubleclick.net  
Duration: 13 months

Name: _gads  
Sender: .chordify.net  
Duration: 2 years

We always take a critical look at which cookies we will allow for our services. Cookies contribute to the best possible operation of our services, and we therefore advise you to accept them and to also retain them after a session. You can easily delete cookies from your devices. The following is a list with the most used browsers and a link to the way you can delete your cookies in your browser:

  * [Opera](http://help.opera.com/Linux/10.10/nl/cookies.html)Groningen, 20 April 2018
